welcome back to another audacity
欢迎回到另一个大胆的地方
tutorial in this video we're going to be
在这段视频中 我们将成为
looking at the vocoder effect within
查看内部的声码器效果
audacity to create sort of like a
大胆地创造出一种类似于
robotic voice and more or less I just
机器人的声音 或多或少 我只是
want to do this tutorial to show you
我想做这篇教程来向你展示
some things that we haven't yet covered
有些事情我们还没有讲到
in audacity we working with tracks and
在胆大妄为的情况下 我们处理轨道和
mono tracks but if you just want to
单声道曲目 但如果您只想
create the robotic voice audacity
创造机器人的声音胆量
actually isn't the best tool for that at
实际上并不是最好的工具 在
least not this vocoder plug-in or effect
至少不是这个声码器插件或效果
but what you can do I'll include this
但你能做什么 我会包括这一点
link here to this get covered right
这里链接到此获取正确的内容
github address for this vocoder sort of
此声码器的GitHub地址
tool that this guy wrote up Chris Wilson
这个人写给克里斯·威尔逊的工具
it's really really awesome and so here's
它真的真的很棒 所以这里是
the license for word it's actually it's
Word的许可证它实际上是它
a some sort of open source I was reading
一种我读到的某种开放源代码
through you can read through the license
通过您可以通读许可证
and see the uses for it but basically
看到了它的用处 但基本上
it's really cool and we can check it out
它真的很酷 我们可以去看看
here it's like what it sounds like so
在这里 它就像它听起来那样
you can you can actually upload your own
你可以你实际上可以上传你自己的
input file or we can talk into it live
输入文件 否则我们可以对其进行现场对话
like we can do this hello testing this
就像我们可以做这个Hello测试这个
is TJ free so that's cool oops how do we
TJ是免费的 所以这很酷哦 我们怎么做
stop this goes out of that anyway so
别说了 不管怎么说 这件事已经过去了
include the link to that if you're
包括指向该链接的链接 如果
trying to if you're just wanting to do
如果你只是想做的话
that then cool you don't need to keep
那就酷了 你不需要保存
watching this video but if you keep
在看这段视频 但如果你继续
watching this you're gonna learn some
看着这个 你会学到一些东西
things about audacity you might not have
关于你可能没有的胆量的事情
known before so we're gonna try to use
所以我们要试着用
audacity to create that same effect so
大胆地创造同样的效果 所以
first of all we need to read in some
首先 我们需要读一些
audio so to do that I was record this is
这样做的音频 我是录制的这是
some audio that will make sound like I
一些音频会发出像我这样的声音
say a robotic voice alright oh and I
说一个机器人的声音 好吧 哦和我
lied first of all let's actually go to
首先是谎言 让我们真正去
tracks and we'll go add new because we
我们会去添加新的曲目 因为我们
want this to be a mono track which means
我希望这是一首单声道 这意味着
there's not a left and a right channel
没有左通道和右通道
it's just a single channel this audio
这只是一个单声道的音频
will be in a robotic voice okay so we
会用机器人的声音好的 所以我们
just have a single channel now if yours
现在只有一个频道 如果是你的
is to do what I did and hit the X there
就是做我做过的事 然后按X键
to delete that that track and then go to
删除该曲目 然后转到
tracks add new mono track okay then in
曲目添加新的单声道曲目可以 然后进入
addition to this we need to have what's
除此之外 我们还需要拥有
called a carrier
被称为承运人
so this is like a carrier audio or
所以这就像是载波音频或
carrier wave that we're gonna kind of
载波 我们将会
mix together with this audio recording
与这段录音混合在一起
to create the vocoder effect the robot
要创建声码器效果 请使用机器人
robotic voice effect so we're going to
机器人语音效果 所以我们要
generate like we've done in the past
像我们过去所做的那样生成
tutorials we're just gonna generate a
我们只需要生成一个教程
tone and we can try some different ones
语气 我们可以试试不同的
so the Sawtooths pretty good I'm going
所以索图斯一家很好 我要走了
to take this frequency down to maybe 240
把这个频率降到240
and we'll take the amplitude amplitudes
我们会用波幅
fine let's try this
好的 我们试试这个吧
oh whoops control Z we need it to be on
哦 哎呀 控制Z 我们需要它开着
its own track so let's add another track
它自己的曲目 所以让我们添加另一首曲目
in here for another mono track and then
在这里播放另一首单声道 然后
we'll do that so we go generate and then
我们会这样做的 这样我们就可以生成
we go tone 240 that should be good and
我们的音调是240 这应该很好
we'll see how this sounds whoa oh my
我们会看到这听起来如何哇哦我的天
goodness that's terrible right so that's
天哪 这太可怕了 对 所以这就是
super high-pitched apologize about that
超高音调为此道歉
let's let's take this but we could we
我们拿着这个吧 但我们可以
could generate it differently but let's
可以以不同的方式生成它 但让我们
just come here and we'll just slow this
来这里 我们会放慢脚步
speed like super super down okay so that
速度就像超级超级减速好的
speeds and slowed down now and now if we
时不时地减速 如果我们
play it it might not be quite as quite
玩吧 它可能不会那么安静
high-pitched okay perfect this is like
高音 好的 完美的 这就像
it's actually very low I'm gonna click
它实际上非常低 我要点击
over here if we do control I it'll cut
在这里 如果我们真的控制它 它会切断
this portion we can just delete that and
这部分我们可以直接删除 然后
then this can click up here and control
然后点击这里 控制
I kind of just cuts the clip wherever
我只是把片段剪到任何地方
we're at I'll double click and delete so
我们在这里 我会双击并删除它
now we have two clips that are about the
现在我们有两个关于
same length we want to make one the left
同样的长度 我们想要一个在左边
channel so I'm gonna make our voice out
频道 所以我要发出我们的声音
of the left
左翼的
we'll make it be the left channel and
我们会让它成为左声道
make this carrier way be out of the
让这条承运人的路不再是
right channel and then when we play each
右频道 然后当我们播放每个频道时
one so well this should be playing out
一场如此出色的比赛 这场比赛应该会上演
of the left ear left speaker or left ear
左耳左耳扬声器或左耳
of your headphones and this should be
你的耳机 这应该是
playing out of the right ear of your
从你的右耳弹出
headphones down here if we go so perfect
如果我们这么完美 耳机就放在这里
and I'm not sure how so good to route
我也不知道怎么才能
this carrier wave is actually a lot
这个载波其实很多
slower than I had intended for it to be
比我预想的要慢
but we'll see how this sounds all right
但我们会看看这听起来怎么样
so we take it off mute now and then we
所以我们时不时地把它换成静音
need to actually combine these together
需要实际地将这些组合在一起
so that it's one audio instead of two
所以它是一个音频而不是两个
separate tracks we want to be one stereo
分开的音轨我们想成为一个立体声
track
轨道
to do that we go up to well first of all
要做到这一点 我们首先要做的是
we have to let them both so we go to
我们必须让他们两个都去 所以我们去
select and then we go to tracks and we
选择 然后我们转到曲目 我们
go in all tracks that selects both of
进入同时选择这两个选项的所有曲目
these and then we go to tracks resample
这些 然后我们转到轨迹重新采样
oh I'm sorry okay no we don't if we go
哦 对不起 好的 不 如果我们去的话就不会了
to tracks mix and then we go to a mix
到曲目混音 然后我们去混音
and render and now look it just changes
和渲染 现在看起来只是改变了
this so now they are just all they're
所以现在他们就是他们的全部
just one track a left channel and the
只有一首曲子 一个左声道和
right channel and then if we play it we
正确的频道 如果我们播放它 我们
still have the what do we do listen the
还有我们该怎么做才能听
left and this and the right but it's
左 这 右 但这是
just all together now and now what we do
只是现在和现在一起我们所做的
we select the whole thing by
我们通过以下方式选择整个产品
double-clicking it'll select both
双击它将同时选中两个
channels since they're all in one track
频道 因为它们都在一个曲目中
and then we just go to effects and
然后我们就去特效中心
vocoders all the way down here's click
所有的声码器都在这里点击
if you're unless maybe you can see it if
如果你是 除非你能看到
you have higher resolution than I do in
你的分辨率比我高
this video and then click on vocoder and
这个视频 然后点击声码器和
then here's where we can change the
然后 我们可以在这里更改
settings for this so right now I'll just
设置 所以现在我只想
hit preview and see how it sounds so
点击预览 看看它听起来如何
that's not too bad by default I had
默认情况下 这还不算太差
already played with a little bit if you
我已经玩过一点了 如果你
go back to defaults this is what it
回到默认设置 这就是它
might sound like for you see so that's
可能听起来像你看到的 所以那是
like really you can hardly hear what's
就像真的你几乎听不到什么
going on there maybe we'll turn we'll
往前走 也许我们会转身 我们会
keep this up so we just want to play
继续这样 所以我们只想玩
around and see if we can get something
看看我们能不能搞到点什么
to change here a little bit that carrier
在这里稍微改变一下那个载体
waves really throwing us off so it
海浪真的把我们抛到一边 所以它
sounds like we're super way down in like
听起来我们像是在超级下沉
a tunnel I think we want to do something
一条隧道我想我们要做点什么
like this more try this so what this is
像这样 再试试这个 这是什么？
actually really doing just so you know
实际上真的只是想让你知道
so it's taking this wave and it's
所以它正在利用这股浪潮 它
applying it oh it did that I wouldn't
应用它 哦 它起作用了 我不会
apply the effect but we were we were we
应用效果 但我们就是我们就是我们
were doing it so let's go back to
我们正在做这件事所以让我们回到
vocoder
声码器
let's select everything go to vocoder so
让我们选择一切转到声码器 所以
I was just preview I didn't I didn't
我只是在预览我不是我不是
apply but if we hit OK it'll actually
申请 但如果我们点击OK 它实际上会
what it does it'll actually merge those
它所做的实际上会合并那些
together so we start seeing patterns
这样我们就开始看到模式
here see these patterns of these spikes
在这里看到这些钉子的图案
we're seeing these patterns happen
我们看到这些模式正在发生
everywhere work every time our carrier
我们的承运人每次在任何地方都能工作
wave had a spike and so it's actually
海浪有一个尖峰 所以实际上
creating kind of this effect anyway
不管怎样 都是在创造这样的效果
that's the way the vocoder works and so
这就是声码器的工作方式 所以
you can play around with it but your
你可以玩它 但你的
carrier wave adjusting that is gonna
载波调整将会是
change a lot how it sounds and that's
很大程度上改变了它的发音
what that website and that web tools
那个网站和那个网络工具
does a much better than audacity it just
比胆大妄为要好得多
has much more dynamic input so you can
具有更多的动态输入 因此您可以
create the same sound in audacity it
在大胆中创造出同样的声音
just won't be nearly as quickly because
只是不会那么快 因为
you can't use those sliders and drag and
你不能用那些滑块和拖拽
drop and do it instantly with live audio
使用现场音频 即可轻松完成
so that other none other tool is a much
因此 其他没有其他工具是一个很大的
much better resource but I just want to
更好的资源 但我只是想
teach you how to do it in audacity
教你如何大胆地做这件事
anyway so that you can learn how to do
不管怎样 这样你就可以学会怎么做了
that appreciate you watching and go
感谢你看着就走
ahead and like links share some if you
前面的链接和Like链接分享一些 如果你
create something using that vocoder tool
使用声码器工具创建一些内容
I'd love to see like what you share with
我很乐意看到你分享的东西
what or what you create so go ahead and
你创造了什么 所以 去吧
share that in the comments below and
在下面的评论中分享这一点并
hope to see you in a video soon
希望很快能在视频中看到你